hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to look at
some of the options which are available
to the normal users and the admin users
in a multi-user workspace apart from
checking in checking out and update all
which we have already seen
so some of the other options which we
are going to talk about is a way to look
at all the changes which have been done
to any particular object
it could be from any particular user if
you are a user or admin user it doesn't
matter you can still see the changes
which have been done by other users
then we can also look at the checkout
details so this will basically tell you
if that object has been checked out by
someone else and who has actually
checked out that particular object
and if you are an admin user you can
even revoke the checkout on a particular
object so that it is made available to
all the users again
so let's see how we can do all of this
uh for this particular purpose I have
created another user under all users
which is called test okay and we are
going to log in with this particular
user now so let's go ahead and close
this workspace
and now I am going to login with the
test user
so here I am going to enter the username
and password
and then click on login
and now what we are going to do is
basically check out a particular folder
here so let's say we check out this tc01
okay so I'm going to check out this
folder
and then I'm going to close this
particular workspace without checking in
this changes okay
so I'm going to close this and subscribe
Commander will ask me if I want to check
in and I will say no this is on purpose
and then we are again going to login
with another different user which is
like an admin user
and then we will see how we can revoke
the changes on that particular object
and whether we can see the checkout
details for that particular object and
the change details
so here instead of test I am going to
login as admin and again admin
click on login
now let's go to that particular folder
and here you will see the difference
that in tc01 a red bar is shown on the
left hand side which means it has been
checked out by a different user
now uh until that user doesn't check in
those changes into this folder I cannot
actually perform anything here so I
cannot create any test case any folder
or anything else okay
so now uh the options which we are
talking about now if I right click on
this uh there is an option called show
latest change details so when you click
on this you will see that it will show
you the name the time the change was
done and the user who made this change
okay
so that will show you uh the change
details and then show checkout details
the second option so it will show you
what time it was checked out by which
user and the name of the folder or the
object so these options will basically
help you to find out if some changes
have been made by some other user or if
some object has been checked out and if
you want to work on that particular
object you can reach out to that
particular user if you know uh who has
actually checked out this particular
folder right
now since this is an admin user I can
also go ahead and revoke this checkout
now few things to remember before you
revoke a particular checkout that the
changes will be discarded okay so no
matter uh if you try to check in later
on uh these changes will not be merged
or available in the workspace once this
is revoked
so if you want you can still revoke the
checkout as an admin user it is not
available with any other user okay you
need to have the admin permissions in
order to perform this change
now right click on the particular object
which you want to revoke the checkout
and there you will find an option called
Reebok checkout
now click on this and Tosca will then
warn you that all changes in this object
will be discarded so click on OK
and then you will see that now this
folder is no more checked out and you
can now perform all the different
operations which you want to but first
obviously you need to check this out
right
so now I can check out this folder and
now I can create a test case
um or a test case folder inside this
particular test object right
and then I can check in all the changes
which I have done and then everything
becomes normal again
so these are all the options which are
available to a particular user and admin
user on a multi-user workspace and this
is how you can revoke checkouts you can
look at the checkout details or you can
even look at the latest change details
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video